<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monica W. Gerber</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Monica W. Gerber</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A little bit of Monica in my life</title>
      <link>/2018/03/little-bit-of-monica/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/little-bit-of-monica/</guid>
      <description>One analysis in the R community that caught my attention is Hilary Parker’s analysis of the most poisoned baby name in US history. I was surprised that my own name didn’t show up in the analysis. If Hilary had a huge loss in 1993, what happened to Monica in 1999?
For a period when I was a kid the name ‘Monica’ is what made the adults turn down the NPR broadcast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on rstudio::conf 2018</title>
      <link>/2018/02/reflections-on-rstudio-conf-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/reflections-on-rstudio-conf-2018/</guid>
      <description>I have a confession. The first time I used R, when I was a Freshman at Reed College and taking Math 141, I hated it. At the time, R was something that intimidated me and seemed to add more work to my schedule. Oh, how have things changed! Years later I started using R again
What makes a successful conference experience? Coming away from the rstudio::conf 2018 with a feeling of excitement and motivation to get started on projects and to conribute to the R community is a good sign of success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, world!</title>
      <link>/2018/01/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>About my work My name is Monica Gerber and I am a Biostatistician located in Boston, Massachusetts. I started working at Massachusetts General Hospital (MGH) in January 2015, when I joined the Department of Psychiatry to work in a research group focused on population mental health. Currently, I work in General Academic Pediatrics and the Center for Community Health Improvement (CCHI).
At MGH I have the pleasure of working on many research and evaluation projects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>