<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Monica W. Gerber</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Monica W. Gerber</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Roundup of growth chart packages</title>
      <link>/2018/07/roundup-of-growth-chart-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/roundup-of-growth-chart-packages/</guid>
      <description>At rOpenSci’s annual unconf, I suggested a project to work on functions that convert physical growth measurements into z-scores and percentiles. For example, researchers in the United States studying childhood obesity often calculate the BMI z-score or percentage of the 95th percentile of BMI from nationally representative survey data.
During the process of brainstorming and working on this project, the team1 I was working with found out some related R packages that do this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I’ve learned about using REDCap with R</title>
      <link>/2018/06/what-i-ve-learned-about-using-redcap-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/what-i-ve-learned-about-using-redcap-with-r/</guid>
      <description>When I started at my current job back fresh out of grad school in January 2015, I had only coded in SAS1 and the the lab I joined was storing data in SPSS spreadsheets–1 file for each patient (:scream:). As you can imagine, I needed to figure out something better and fast. Luckily, my institution had REDCap so I started getting us more organized by putting our data in a REDCap database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing experimental data with ridgeline plots</title>
      <link>/2018/05/visualizing-outcomes-in-epidemiology-with-joy-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/visualizing-outcomes-in-epidemiology-with-joy-plots/</guid>
      <description>I’m a bit late to the ridgeline plot craze of 2017, but recently became a fan of using these plots for visualizing body mass index (BMI; a measure used to screen for body fatness) outcomes in clinical research. We often measure BMI at multiple time points during a clinical trial, and physicians want to know how the distribution of BMI is shifting. Ridgeline plots are a perfect way to look at these distributions over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving biostatistics workflows with purr</title>
      <link>/2018/04/improving-biostatistics-workflows-with-purr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/improving-biostatistics-workflows-with-purr/</guid>
      <description>Some datasets
 Data is plural https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural CDC ? https://www.cdc.gov/  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on rstudio::conf 2018</title>
      <link>/2018/04/reflections-on-rstudio-conf-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/reflections-on-rstudio-conf-2018/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a couple of months since rstudio::conf 2018 and I’m still mulling over what I learned in 2 days in San Diego. I grew up in the sunshine of San Diego, so it was good to be back and also feel inspired by the amazing energy of the R community. Here’s a reflection on what the conference was like, what ideas I’ve been running with, and how what I learned will change what I do over the course of the next year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping the MMWR with rvest</title>
      <link>/2018/03/scraping-the-mmwr-with-rvest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/scraping-the-mmwr-with-rvest/</guid>
      <description>rvest in action First, we need to create a html document from the URL of the page we want using read_html().
library(rvest) cdc_site &amp;lt;- read_html(&amp;quot;http://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/65/wr/mm6545a2.htm?s_cid=mm6545a2_w&amp;quot;) After we have the html document, we need to select part of the document using CSS selectors. I read up on selectorgadget (see rvest, /Library/Frameworks/R.framework/Versions/3.4/Resources/library/rvest, selectorgadget, selectorgadget.Rmd, Selectorgadget, selectorgadget.R, selectorgadget.html) to help me figure out which selector to use. However, for this task, I found it easier to just extract the type of element we want, which is the table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A little bit of Monica in my life</title>
      <link>/2018/03/little-bit-of-monica/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/little-bit-of-monica/</guid>
      <description>One analysis in the R community that caught my attention is Hilary Parker’s analysis of the most poisoned baby name in US history. I was surprised that my own name didn’t show up in the analysis. If Hilary had a huge loss in 1993, what happened to Monica in 1999?
For a period when I was a kid the name ‘Monica’ is what made the adults turn down the NPR broadcast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, world!</title>
      <link>/2018/01/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>About my work My name is Monica Gerber and I am a Biostatistician located in Boston, Massachusetts. I started working at Massachusetts General Hospital (MGH) in January 2015, when I joined the Department of Psychiatry to work in a research group focused on population mental health. Currently, I work in General Academic Pediatrics and the Center for Community Health Improvement (CCHI).
At MGH I have the pleasure of working on many research and evaluation projects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>